## Florin LIPAN

## About

I'm a Ruby/Rust developer with a devops background, leadership experience and a passion for building products. I know my way around AWS, Kubernetes, Docker and Linux. I can speak SQL to your database and GraphQL to your clients. I'm familiar with HTML, CSS, Javascript, Hotwire, and what makes a good UI/UX. I value clean, simple, boring code and try to be pragmatic while keeping my standards high. I can write concise, well structured documentation. I enjoy learning, teaching and being self-organized.

Dο	rcn	nal

Email <u>florinlipan@gmail.com</u>

GitHub / Projects <a href="https://github.com/lipanski">https://github.com/lipanski</a>

Website / Blog <a href="https://lipanski.com">https://lipanski.com</a>
Place of residence Berlin, Germany

Languages Solid English, German, Romanian. Some French.

Experience

May 2022 - Present Kraken / Engineering Manager (Rust)

Managing a team of developers for one of the largest crypto trading platform in the world. I'm responsible for planning, contributing to RFCs, code review and release management, providing feedback and context, recruiting and some hands-on action.

May 2020 – April 2022 Chatterbug / Staff Engineer

A hands-on experience building a complex language learning and video streaming platform together with the founders of GitHub. I improved the website performance on numerous occasions, nurtured the Rails monolith and designed advanced GraphQL APIs. I helped other developers in their daily work through pairing, code reviews, planning and patience. I introduced Turbo Streams, Stimulus and GraphQL Subscriptions to the stack, significantly reducing our development time. I learned a lot about developing a successful product with a very small team and lean processes.

Jul. 2018 - Apr. 2020 Blacklane / Head of Engineering (Platform)

Providing high-level technical guidance to the Blacklane Platform teams (Infrastructure, Geolocation, Payment, Back-office, Salesforce, Internal APIs, ~15 engineers), trying to empower developers whenever I can, but getting my hands dirty when I'm needed. I'm handling recruiting and interviews, providing feedback in 1:1 sessions and mentoring team members. I'm trying to keep engineering standards high, apps running smoothly and people engaged and happy.

Blacklane / Lead Backend Developer (Ruby)

A merry mix of backend development, devops, software architecture and management tasks. I helped tame the Rails monolith, designed and partially developed the new Booking API and developed various (micro)services in Sinatra or Rack using MySQL, Postgres, Redis, Sidekiq, Puma and others. I got deeper into ops, got familiar with a wide range of AWS services from VPCs to CloudFormation and built our infrastructure around Ansible. Over the course of the last year, we shifted towards Kubernetes and Docker. I introduced new processes, handled technical interviews and performed product management tasks. I improved the performance of our systems and lived to see some beefy infrastructure migration Sundays.

Feb. 2014 - Aug. 2014 Blacklane / Backend Developer (Ruby)

Nov. 2012 - Jan. 2014 Axonic / Full Stack Developer (Ruby on Rails)

I developed a fairly complex product from scratch, while being the only developer on the project. Working closely with the CEO, I learned not just full stack Ruby on Rails but also what's important to customers, how to plan and how to build a product.

Dec. 2010 - Aug. 2012 **Axonic / Full Stack Developer (PHP5, Symfony)** 

Apr. 2009 - Jul. 2010 Pi Technologies / Developer (PHP, CMS, Javascript)

Education

Sep. 2014 - Jun. 2018

2010 - 2011 Karlsruhe Institute of Technology M. Sc. Informatics (discontinued)

2006 - 2010 **Technical University of Cluj-Napoca** B. Sc. Informatics, 240 ECTS Points, 9.5/10